# Manda Venkatasudheerkumar

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India



venkatasudheermanda@gmail.com



+91 8688088368



linkedin.com/in/venkata-sudheer

### **Summary**

Experienced Certification Specialist with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Microsoft Word, python, PHP, vuejs, Networking, and HTML. Strong information technology professional with a Bachelor of Technology (B Tech) focused in CSE from SRM University.

### **Experience**

#### 90/2 Web Developer

90bar2

Jan 2020 - Present (9 months +)

- 1. created Static website
- 2. Created internal login management with leave management using php and sql

live demo: https://dashboard.90bar2.com

3. created Ecommerce Mobile Application using Framework7

live demo: https://90bar2.com/ecomerce/

### google assistant developer community program member

**Google Developers** 

Sep 2019 - Present (1 year 1 month +)

I Have Made Action On Google. Action On Google is The Development Platform For Google Assistant. Google Assistant is an Artificial Intelligence-powered Virtual Assistant Developed By Google that was Primarily Available on Mobile Devices and Smart Home. Unlike the Company's Previous Virtual Assistant, Google Now, Google Assistant can engage in a two-way conversation. In 2017, the Google Assistant was installed on more than 400 million devices.

Name of My Action is "Ravi Traders". This actions is for chilli powder business.

To Use:

Trigger Google Assistant By:

"OK Google, Talk To Ravi Traders"

OR

you can check my action in https://www.ravimanda.co.in/contact.php page

# Software Engineer

webprogr.com

Jan 2019 - Jan 2020 (1 year 1 month)

After entering in to this company i have learned how to make hybrid apps with the help of cordova (to genrate APK).

What i have learned after joining in this company

1 Mobile Ui

- 2 Framework7
- 3 Quasar Framework
- 4 Vue js

My projects:

Hybrid app:https://www.amazon.com/Ravi-Traders/dp/B07MZPCXCN/

website:https://www.ravimanda.co.in, https:livenews.ravimanda.co.in using vue js

portfolio example: https://venkatasudheerportfolio.herokuapp.com using vue.js

portfolio: https://venkatasudheer.8b.io

### Certification Courses

**IIHT Ltd** 

Mar 2018 - Jul 2018 (5 months)

I have done with A+(Hardware) and N+(Networking)

In that Courses i have learnt

Hardware:

- 1) Hardware Components of the Computer and Basic things like the types of Processors and ROMS and RAMS
- 2) Architecture of the Computer
- 3) Assemble and Reassemble of the Computer hardware parts
- 4) How to Install Software's in the Computer from Bootloader
- 5) How to break the Computer Password with the help of some software's
- 6) How to dual windows in single Computer

Networking:

- 1) how to route the IP Address from one router to another router
- 2) how to send Messages from Router -Switch Router
- 3) How to Configure the Router and Switch
- 4) Network Layers

# Internship

HP sotware university

Jul 2017 - Aug 2017 (2 months)

I m learning about Hadoop and Big data(HIV, PIG)

# Inplant Training

JP Infotech

Jul 2016 - Jul 2016 (1 month)

I have done PHP, HTML and CSS. And learnt how to code using them in Eclipse.

### **Education**



### SRM University

Bachelor of Technology (BTech), Computer Science Engineering 2014 - 2018

Experienced Certification Specialist with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Microsoft Word, C++, Java, Networking, and HTML. Strong information technology professional with a Bachelor of Technology (B Tech) focused in CSE from SRM University.

Sri Chaitanya College of Education

INTERMEDIATE, Maths, Physics, Chemistry 2012 - 2014

Triveni Public School
10th Class, State Board
2011 - 2012

### **Licenses & Certifications**

- MTML SoloLearn
- PHP SoloLearn
- CSS SoloLearn
- Google digital unlocked Google
  T7W 6SP UQ4
- Search Engine Optimization eMarketing Institute
  CERT00593655-EMI
- FB Facebook Spilt Testing Facebook 49255350
- **Google analytics** Google Developers Issued Apr 2019 Expires Apr 2022

### **Skills**

Digital Marketing • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • HTML • Microsoft Office • Vue.js • PHP • PhpMyAdmin • MySQL